<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Theme Development on Everything is Gray</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/tags/theme-development/</link><description>Recent content in Theme Development on Everything is Gray</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>James Barclay</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 21:24:19 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://everythingisgray.com/tags/theme-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Version 0.5 of Simplixity Is Now Live</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/22/version-0.5-of-simplixity-is-now-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/22/version-0.5-of-simplixity-is-now-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I submitted an update to my WordPress theme Simplixity, which improves how images are handled in posts and fixes an issue that existed while no widgets were activated in the admin panel. You can view and download it &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/simplixity">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already begun working on the next update, which should include an easily customizable &lt;code>client.css&lt;/code> file, for making quick changes to the theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do Hosted Solutions Threaten WordPress and Other Blogging Platforms?</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/02/do-hosted-solutions-threaten-wordpress-and-other-blogging-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/02/do-hosted-solutions-threaten-wordpress-and-other-blogging-platforms/</guid><description>&lt;p>With completely hosted solutions like &lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/">Squarespace&lt;/a> becoming more and more popular everyday, should content creators using WordPress and similar platforms be concerned? What about the designers and developers that create plugins and themes for these systems?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for blogging/content management systems like WordPress to survive, there needs to be a thriving community of developers and users alike. There&amp;rsquo;s certainly no shortage of either in the WordPress community, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see it going anywhere anytime soon. Truthfully, I find that there is a place for both a DIY solution like WordPress and an entirely hosted solution like &lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/">Squarespace&lt;/a>. I personally prefer having to dig deep into the CSS, XHTML, and PHP to truly customize a WordPress blog/site, though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wordpress Theme "Simplixity" Is Now Available on the WordPress Theme Directory</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/03/31/wordpress-theme-simplixity-is-now-available-on-the-wordpress-theme-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/03/31/wordpress-theme-simplixity-is-now-available-on-the-wordpress-theme-directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>After correcting a minor mistake that I made to my credit link, the folks at WordPress accepted my new theme and will be featuring it on the WordPress theme directory page. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview or download the theme you can do so &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/simplixity">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>/* Hello World */</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2008/10/31/-hello-world-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2008/10/31/-hello-world-/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the next few months I will be working on developing a WordPress theme. I am currently using one of my favorite themes from the WordPress theme directory, which I will be editing in hopes of becoming more familiar with PHP and WordPress in general. Keep posted to see where this all ends up.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>