<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Octopress on Everything is Gray</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/categories/octopress/</link><description>Recent content in Octopress on Everything is Gray</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>James Barclay</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 23:44:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://everythingisgray.com/categories/octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Migrating From WordPress to Octopress</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2013/06/15/on-migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2013/06/15/on-migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having recently made the decision to migrate my blog from WordPress to &lt;a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress&lt;/a> I decided I would share my findings in hopes that someone else will benefit from them, and so I can refer back to this post should I need to do something similar in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary reason I decided to move to a statically generated site is because I found myself spending more time worrying about whether my site was running and was secure than I did writing. My site was hacked last year because I was running an outdated version of WordPress, and since moving to a new host, (Amazon EC2), I have frequently had to restart MySQL and Apache just to keep the site up. This could be partially due to the fact that I was running the site on a &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/concepts_micro_instances.html">micro instance&lt;/a>, but now that my blog is static I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about that any longer. Another reason why I chose Octopress for my blogging platform is that I like to tinker, and being able to use tools that I&amp;rsquo;m already familiar with and use every day was a huge plus, (Vim, Git, and Markdown, specifically).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>