<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WordPress on Everything is Gray</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/categories/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on Everything is Gray</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>James Barclay</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 23:44:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://everythingisgray.com/categories/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Migrating From WordPress to Octopress</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2013/06/15/on-migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2013/06/15/on-migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having recently made the decision to migrate my blog from WordPress to &lt;a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress&lt;/a> I decided I would share my findings in hopes that someone else will benefit from them, and so I can refer back to this post should I need to do something similar in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary reason I decided to move to a statically generated site is because I found myself spending more time worrying about whether my site was running and was secure than I did writing. My site was hacked last year because I was running an outdated version of WordPress, and since moving to a new host, (Amazon EC2), I have frequently had to restart MySQL and Apache just to keep the site up. This could be partially due to the fact that I was running the site on a &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/concepts_micro_instances.html">micro instance&lt;/a>, but now that my blog is static I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about that any longer. Another reason why I chose Octopress for my blogging platform is that I like to tinker, and being able to use tools that I&amp;rsquo;m already familiar with and use every day was a huge plus, (Vim, Git, and Markdown, specifically).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NextGEN: Cool WordPress Plugin</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/06/16/nextgen-cool-wordpress-plugin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/06/16/nextgen-cool-wordpress-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>After about a month of searching for a WordPress image gallery plugin that is both powerful and easy to use, I came across &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/nextgen-gallery/">NextGEN Gallery&lt;/a>. This plugin is extremely easy to implement, and once activated is easy to maintain/update. I like the fact that you can create multiple galleries and group them together in albums, too. It&amp;rsquo;s also a breeze to update a gallery or album once it&amp;rsquo;s been posted. I&amp;rsquo;m currently using this plugin for my portfolio, (which should include more than a few images soon), and overall I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Version 0.5 of Simplixity Is Now Live</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/22/version-0.5-of-simplixity-is-now-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/22/version-0.5-of-simplixity-is-now-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I submitted an update to my WordPress theme Simplixity, which improves how images are handled in posts and fixes an issue that existed while no widgets were activated in the admin panel. You can view and download it &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/simplixity">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already begun working on the next update, which should include an easily customizable &lt;code>client.css&lt;/code> file, for making quick changes to the theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do Hosted Solutions Threaten WordPress and Other Blogging Platforms?</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/02/do-hosted-solutions-threaten-wordpress-and-other-blogging-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/05/02/do-hosted-solutions-threaten-wordpress-and-other-blogging-platforms/</guid><description>&lt;p>With completely hosted solutions like &lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/">Squarespace&lt;/a> becoming more and more popular everyday, should content creators using WordPress and similar platforms be concerned? What about the designers and developers that create plugins and themes for these systems?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for blogging/content management systems like WordPress to survive, there needs to be a thriving community of developers and users alike. There&amp;rsquo;s certainly no shortage of either in the WordPress community, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see it going anywhere anytime soon. Truthfully, I find that there is a place for both a DIY solution like WordPress and an entirely hosted solution like &lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/">Squarespace&lt;/a>. I personally prefer having to dig deep into the CSS, XHTML, and PHP to truly customize a WordPress blog/site, though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jobtac Uses "Simplixity" Theme for Their WP Blog</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/30/jobtac-uses-simplixity-theme-for-their-wp-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/30/jobtac-uses-simplixity-theme-for-their-wp-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s become rather amusing for me to find out just who is using my WordPress theme. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s not so flattering, other times it is. The other day I discovered that &lt;a href="http://www.jobtac.com/">Jobtac&lt;/a>, a job posting site for employers and job seekers alike, is using &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/simplixity">Simplixity&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="http://www.jobtac.com/blog/">their blog&lt;/a>. Thanks a lot, guys!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loopthing Uses "Simplixity" Theme for Their Blog</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/17/loopthing-uses-simplixity-theme-for-their-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/17/loopthing-uses-simplixity-theme-for-their-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>While browsing through my HTTP referrers I found that an online business network called &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.loopthing.com/">Loopthing&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is using my WordPress theme for their blog. So far it looks like the blog is somewhat secondary, (the link to it is on the bottom of the page), but I&amp;rsquo;m honored nonetheless. &lt;a href="http://blog.loopthing.com/">Go take a look.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modification of "Simplixity" WordPress Theme</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/08/modification-of-simplixity-wordpress-theme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/04/08/modification-of-simplixity-wordpress-theme/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently discovered that a gentleman named Pete made a modification of my WordPress theme for his own site. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see this being done so early on. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href="http://www.theteacherlist.ca/">The Teacher List&lt;/a>, go check it out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wordpress Theme "Simplixity" Is Now Available on the WordPress Theme Directory</title><link>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/03/31/wordpress-theme-simplixity-is-now-available-on-the-wordpress-theme-directory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://everythingisgray.com/2009/03/31/wordpress-theme-simplixity-is-now-available-on-the-wordpress-theme-directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>After correcting a minor mistake that I made to my credit link, the folks at WordPress accepted my new theme and will be featuring it on the WordPress theme directory page. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview or download the theme you can do so &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/themes/simplixity">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>